<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[SerpicoProject]]></title>
  <link href="https://serpicoproject.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://serpicoproject.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-09-26T18:17:12-07:00</updated>
  <id>https://serpicoproject.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[SerpicoProject]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome RubyZip]]></title>
    <link href="https://serpicoproject.github.io/blog/2016/08/18/long-live-rubyzip/"/>
    <updated>2016-08-18T21:00:01-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://serpicoproject.github.io/blog/2016/08/18/long-live-rubyzip</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Since the beginning Serpico has used ZipRuby for the Zip library. It&rsquo;s done a sufficient job but it is a mess to install on Windows. Gathering up our technical debt <!-- more --> we switched the code to RubyZip along with refactoring the document process. Really RubyZip is a far better option as it&rsquo;s modern, supported, and installs on Windows.</p>

<h1>TLDR</h1>

<p>Serpico runs on Windows now. An installer is soon to follow. =)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Booting Up the Blog and Support]]></title>
    <link href="https://serpicoproject.github.io/blog/2016/08/18/boot/"/>
    <updated>2016-08-18T21:00:01-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://serpicoproject.github.io/blog/2016/08/18/boot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The first commit for Serpico was February 4th, 2013. Since then we&rsquo;ve had dozens of contributors, <!-- more --> thousands of installs, three appearances at BlackHat Arsenal and a little over 50,000 LOCs written. And that just skims the surface. I am so proud to be a part of something like this.</p>

<p>Up to this point each of us has been contributing in our spare time. Internally we were paying it forward to so many people that helped us. However, recently we&rsquo;ve hit a tough point. To be able to support the community with something worth using, we need to take a chance in offering a paid option for enterprise customers.</p>

<p>All of the information is on the Enterprise Purchase page (<a href="https://www.serpicoproject.com/purchase">https://www.serpicoproject.com/purchase</a>) or send an e-mail to enterprise &ndash;at&mdash; serpicoproject.com.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
