<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[SerpicoProject]]></title>
  <link href="https://serpicoproject.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://serpicoproject.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2018-05-18T13:13:23-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://serpicoproject.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[SerpicoProject]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migrating Support to Slack]]></title>
    <link href="https://serpicoproject.github.io/blog/2018/05/16/migrating-support-to-slack/"/>
    <updated>2018-05-16T14:42:11-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://serpicoproject.github.io/blog/2018/05/16/migrating-support-to-slack</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the past few months the team has been migrating Serpico support away from IRC and over to Slack. If you&rsquo;d like access to the Slack channel please e-mail support &ndash;at___ serpicoproject.com or consider purchasing an <a href="https://license.serpicoproject.com">individual license</a> =). As of today, the IRC channel will no long be a monitored platform for support.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Visit Us At Blackhat Arsenal 2017]]></title>
    <link href="https://serpicoproject.github.io/blog/2017/07/22/visit-us-at-blackhat-arsenal-2017/"/>
    <updated>2017-07-22T21:53:41-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://serpicoproject.github.io/blog/2017/07/22/visit-us-at-blackhat-arsenal-2017</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We are presenting at Arsenal BlackHat USA 2017. If you’re at BlackHat next week stop by and check out these new features in action. We’ll be at the Arsenal track on Thursday, July 27th from 10:00am-11:20am.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Serpico 1.2 Feature: Serpico Has Vector Strings]]></title>
    <link href="https://serpicoproject.github.io/blog/2017/07/22/serpico-1-dot-2-feature-serpico-has-vector-strings/"/>
    <updated>2017-07-22T21:45:59-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://serpicoproject.github.io/blog/2017/07/22/serpico-1-dot-2-feature-serpico-has-vector-strings</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you are using either CVSS scoring then you should know it is much easier to add a vector string to your report. <!-- more --></p>

<p>After you click save on a finding the vector string is automatically calculated and added to the DB. To use the vector string in your report, use</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>πc2_vsπ
</span><span class='line'>πc3_vsπ</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>For existing findings you will need to edit and re-save the finding or automate the process.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Serpico Gets Risk Matrix Reporting]]></title>
    <link href="https://serpicoproject.github.io/blog/2017/07/22/serpico-gets-risk-matrix-reporting/"/>
    <updated>2017-07-22T21:25:01-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://serpicoproject.github.io/blog/2017/07/22/serpico-gets-risk-matrix-reporting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the last few weeks thanks to contributors and the Serpico team members’ updates, new report types have been added to the framework. One of the recent additions was the Risk Matrix scoring submitted by geckom. <!-- more --></p>

<p>Similar to other report types, switching to Risk Matrix is simple. Just change the Risk Scoring Algorithm under the Administration menu -&gt; Modify Configurations.</p>

<p><img style="border:1px solid black center" height=100 width=350 src="https://serpicoproject.github.io/images/rixk.jpg"></p>

<p>With Risk Matrix enabled, we find new options when editing or adding a new finding. We have Vulnerability Risk Level, Severity, Severity Rationale, Likelihood and Likelihood Rationale options in our findings.</p>

<p><img style="border:1px solid black center" height=350 width=550 src="https://serpicoproject.github.io/images/risk_matrix.jpg"></p>

<p>If you’re at Black Hat next week stop by and check out these new features in action. We’ll be at the Arsenal track on Thursday, July 27th from 10:00am-11:20am.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Serpico Supports CVSSv3]]></title>
    <link href="https://serpicoproject.github.io/blog/2017/07/22/serpico-supports-cvssv3/"/>
    <updated>2017-07-22T21:10:05-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://serpicoproject.github.io/blog/2017/07/22/serpico-supports-cvssv3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thanks to aconite33 <a href="https://www.twitter.com/zeekzack">@zeekzack</a> and some Serpico team integration, Serpico now supports CVSS version 3. Enabling CVSSv3 reporting is as simple as <!-- more --> going to the Administration menu -&gt; Modify Configurations, and selecting CVSS3 as the Risk Scoring Algorithm.</p>

<p><img style="border:1px solid black center" height=350 width=550 src="https://serpicoproject.github.io/images/cvssv3.jpg"></p>

<p>Now that CVSS3 is enabled, when you edit or add a finding you’ll see the new metric names.</p>

<p><img style="border:1px solid black center" height=350 width=550 src="https://serpicoproject.github.io/images/findings.jpg"></p>

<p>Last but not least, there is a button “CVSS Vector String” which will automatically update the metric value based on a vector string. As an example:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>CVSS:3.0/AV:N/AC:L/PR:N/UI:N/S:C/C:H/I:N/A:N/RL:O/CR:H</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>To round out the new CVSS 3 scoring, we have included a CVSS 3 report template. A copy of the template report can found at <a href="https://github.com/SerpicoProject/Serpico/blob/master/templates/Default%20CVSS%203%20Report.docx">CVSSv3 Report Template</a>, or pulled directly from the main Serpico repository.</p>

<p>If you’re at Black Hat next week stop by and check out these new features in action. We’ll be at
the Arsenal track on Thursday, July 27th from 10:00am-11:20am.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Serpico 1.2 Feature: Plug-In Framework]]></title>
    <link href="https://serpicoproject.github.io/blog/2017/07/22/serpico-1-dot-2-feature-plug-in-framework/"/>
    <updated>2017-07-22T20:47:54-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://serpicoproject.github.io/blog/2017/07/22/serpico-1-dot-2-feature-plug-in-framework</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Serpico team has been hard at work adding features to lessen the burden of reporting. One of our latest features <!-- more --> is the Plugin framework. One of the goals we had for the plug-in framework was to allow a developer to overwrite parts of Serpico. Plug-ins give developers tremendous power and flexibility to extent Serpico to meet their specific needs. With plug-ins, developers no longer have to worry about their secret sauce getting overwritten when updating the core framework.</p>

<p>Our first example is the Auth_Mode plug-in described in <a href="https://www.serpicoproject.com/blog/2016/12/17/monkey-patching-%20serpico/">Monkey Patching Serpico</a>. As a developer, the Auth_Mode plugin is a <em>must</em> have and speeds up development time. Our second example plug-in deals with custom User Defined Variables as shown in <a href="https://www.serpicoproject.com/blog/2016/12/17/udv-worksheet-example/">UDV Worksheet</a>. This post is a great example of using a plug-in to extend the framework. With some additional tweaks and creativity, this plug-in can be used to assist in gap style assessments such as those used for HIPPA or PCI.</p>

<p>If you’re at Black Hat next week stop by and check out these new features in action. We’ll be at the Arsenal track on Thursday, July 27th from 10:00am-11:20am.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Serpico on a Beaglebone - Arsenal 2016]]></title>
    <link href="https://serpicoproject.github.io/blog/2017/04/21/serpico-on-a-beaglebone/"/>
    <updated>2017-04-21T08:20:32-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://serpicoproject.github.io/blog/2017/04/21/serpico-on-a-beaglebone</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just wanted to share a cool image from last year&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.blackhat.com/us-16/arsenal.html#serpico">BlackHat Arsenal</a>
<img style="border:1px solid black center" height=350 width=550 src="https://serpicoproject.github.io/images/beaglebone.jpg"></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>This is Serpico installed and running on a BeagleBone Green (small form factor, 512MB DDR3)</p>

<p>From the beginning we&rsquo;ve tried to keep Serpico&rsquo;s memory footprint small. The original Serpico (circa 2014) was kept on a Raspberry Pi. We would bring it on site to engagements and all connect to collaborate on reports.</p>

<p>Thanks should go to the always awesome Michael Belton, Optiv for sponsoring the BeagleBone Greens last year, and <a href="https://github.com/Petessss">Pete</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[UDV Worksheet - Plugin Tradecraft]]></title>
    <link href="https://serpicoproject.github.io/blog/2016/12/17/udv-worksheet-example/"/>
    <updated>2016-12-17T18:44:02-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://serpicoproject.github.io/blog/2016/12/17/udv-worksheet-example</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://github.com/SerpicoProject/SerpicoPlugins/tree/master/UDV_Worksheet">UDV Worksheet</a> plugin allows administrators to create questions that can be filled out by consultants. The answers are inserted into the report as User Defined Variables<!-- more -->. It is really handy because it can centralize questions that are typically added in an assessment while still allowing them to be used throughout a report template.</p>

<p><img style="border:1px solid black" height=350 width=550 src="https://serpicoproject.github.io/images/UDV_Worksheet_1.png"></p>

<p><img style="border:1px solid black" height=350 width=450 src="https://serpicoproject.github.io/images/UDV_Worksheet_2.png"></p>

<p>It also illustrates the use of multiple databases in a plugin.</p>

<h2>Multiple Databases</h2>

<p>One of the cool things about plugins is you can have multiple database connections. Two things are required, a connection to the database <a href="https://github.com/SerpicoProject/SerpicoPlugins/blob/master/UDV_Worksheet/master_udv.rb#L7">1</a></p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>DataMapper.setup(:udv, "sqlite://#{Dir.pwd}/plugins/UDV_Worksheet/udv.db")</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>A call to the secondary database is done using the Datamapper repository method (<a href="https://github.com/SerpicoProject/SerpicoPlugins/blob/master/UDV_Worksheet/routes.rb#L23">https://github.com/SerpicoProject/SerpicoPlugins/blob/master/UDV_Worksheet/routes.rb#L23</a>).</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'> DataMapper.repository(:udv) {
</span><span class='line'>      @questions = Questions.all(:report_id =&gt; 0)
</span><span class='line'>  }</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Note, in this case we use a SQLite database. But with the addition of a different data mapper gem (e.g. dm-mysql-adapter), you could make a connection to another database.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monkey Patching Serpico]]></title>
    <link href="https://serpicoproject.github.io/blog/2016/12/17/monkey-patching-serpico/"/>
    <updated>2016-12-17T11:54:57-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://serpicoproject.github.io/blog/2016/12/17/monkey-patching-serpico</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monkey_patch">Monkey Patching</a> is a technique to modify the way a dynamic language operates at run time. One of the goals we had from the plug-in framework is that it would allow a developer to overwrite parts of Serpico. <!-- more --> Specifically, a developer could completely modify the way some part of their reporting process works with a minimal amount of code.</p>

<p>This blog post is about the <a href="https://github.com/SerpicoProject/SerpicoPlugins/tree/master/Auth_Mode">Auth_Mode</a> plugin which is a simple example of a plugin to monkey patch Serpico.</p>

<h2>Warning</h2>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>Auth_Mode is powerful, it completely disables authentication and authorization. When installed and enabled, any user who visits the server is a full administrator without logging in.</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>I use Auth_Mode to speed up my development process; specifically when I want to change quickly between users or as a full administrator without using a password or navigation.</p>

<h2>run.rb</h2>

<p>There is only one file in the Auth_Mode plugin; <a href="https://github.com/SerpicoProject/SerpicoPlugins/blob/master/Auth_Mode/run.rb">run.rb</a>. First, run.rb overrides the Serpico server itself with the line:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>...
</span><span class='line'>  class Server &lt; Sinatra::Application
</span><span class='line'>...</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>When this code is loaded, any methods contained in run.rb will override existing Server.rb methods. Note, the rest of the server is left as is.</p>

<p>Next, run.rb overrides the is_administrator? call which is used throughout Serpico to check if a user is an administrator:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'> def is_administrator?
</span><span class='line'>      return true
</span><span class='line'>  end</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>And that&rsquo;s it! Everytime the server looks to check if a user is an administrator, this method is overridden to always return true.</p>

<h2>Other Applications</h2>

<p>I kept this plug-in short on purpose. There are many many other ways you could apply similar ideas. For example:</p>

<ul>
<li>Override report generation to always store on another server</li>
<li>Third party logging</li>
<li>Extend the API</li>
<li>Parse input data on another server</li>
</ul>


<h2>Note</h2>

<p>As of today you will need to use a Master branch version of Serpico for this to work. Release 1.1.1 which should be out within the next few weeks will natively support this functionality.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Release 1.1.0 is out]]></title>
    <link href="https://serpicoproject.github.io/blog/2016/12/05/release-1-dot-1-0/"/>
    <updated>2016-12-05T15:33:36-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://serpicoproject.github.io/blog/2016/12/05/release-1-dot-1-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Release <a href="https://github.com/SerpicoProject/Serpico/releases/tag/1.1.0">1.1.0</a> went out on Friday. It&rsquo;s <!-- more --> a relatively small release feature wise but there are a couple of things to call out:</p>

<h2>Serpico Plug-in Framework</h2>

<p>For a while we&rsquo;ve wanted a way to test out functionality without requiring it be in the master branch. Plug-ins are an awesome way to do this. You can add completely new functionality (with access to the DB, etc) in a small and easy to test/maintain package. More blog posts about this on the way. For now check out <a href="https://github.com/SerpicoProject/Serpico/wiki/Plug-ins">here</a> and in the <a href="https://github.com/SerpicoProject/SerpicoPlugins/wiki/Main-Page">Serpico Plugins Project</a>.</p>

<h2>Automated Build Process</h2>

<p>Our resident deployment ninja <a href="https://github.com/Petessss">Petessss</a> put together an automated build process. This has cut down on the time it takes to create a build considerably. The goal is get releases out for testing more often.</p>

<h2>Markdown sanity check</h2>

<p>We implemented a feature that will report errors in the markdown when attempting to save a finding. Previously this could break a report and was annoying to troubleshoot. We should be improving the markdown process more in the future.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Serpico 1.0.0 is out]]></title>
    <link href="https://serpicoproject.github.io/blog/2016/09/30/serpico-1-dot-0-is-out/"/>
    <updated>2016-09-30T13:40:59-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://serpicoproject.github.io/blog/2016/09/30/serpico-1-dot-0-is-out</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>BlackHat Arsenal marked the first alpha release of Serpico. Today, after a major effort in the release cycle from Petessss we have hit <a href="https://github.com/SerpicoProject/Serpico/releases/tag/1.0">1.0.0</a>. There&rsquo;s <!-- more --> a lot of stuff in here (55 issues closed since last release; numerous features and bugs) but there are a few things I want to call out:</p>

<h2>Windows and OS X Installer</h2>

<p>Using Serpico on OS X and Windows just got way easier thanks to a mega effort from <a href="https://github.com/Petessss">Petessss</a>. Personally, I am really excited about this because I can hammer out reports in my Windows VM and use a clean instance every time.</p>

<h2>Bulk Upload and Image Insertion Auto-Complete</h2>

<p>Multiple attachments can now be uploaded at once. This means uploading a directory of screenshots instead of one at a time. Furthermore, just type the character &ldquo;[&rdquo; into the Proof of Concept section and your list of images is loaded similar to GitHub autocomplete. This should hopefully speed up your reporting time.</p>

<p><img tyle="border:5px solid black" height=450 width=700 src="https://serpicoproject.github.io/images/BulkUpload.gif"></p>

<h2>New Logo</h2>

<p><a href="https://github.com/ccammilleri">ccammilleri</a> drew up a rad logo. It&rsquo;s on the front page now and if you see us at a conference, ask for stickers.</p>

<h2>RubyZip</h2>

<p>Moving from ZipRuby to RubyZip allowed us to start using Windows. This actually took quite a bit of testing, but glad to see it in there.</p>

<h2>Route Splitting</h2>

<p>Routes are now split into multiple files. This will pave the way for plug-ins and easier debugging.</p>

<h2>Presentations as PDFs</h2>

<p>There is a new link to generate your presentation as a PDF ; much easier to hand to a client.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome RubyZip]]></title>
    <link href="https://serpicoproject.github.io/blog/2016/08/19/long-live-rubyzip/"/>
    <updated>2016-08-19T00:00:01-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://serpicoproject.github.io/blog/2016/08/19/long-live-rubyzip</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Since the beginning Serpico has used ZipRuby for the Zip library. It&rsquo;s done a sufficient job but it is a mess to install on Windows. Gathering up our technical debt <!-- more --> we switched the code to RubyZip along with refactoring the document process. Really RubyZip is a far better option as it&rsquo;s modern, supported, and installs on Windows.</p>

<h1>TLDR</h1>

<p>Serpico runs on Windows now. An installer is soon to follow. =)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Booting Up the Blog and Support]]></title>
    <link href="https://serpicoproject.github.io/blog/2016/08/19/boot/"/>
    <updated>2016-08-19T00:00:01-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://serpicoproject.github.io/blog/2016/08/19/boot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The first commit for Serpico was February 4th, 2013. Since then we&rsquo;ve had dozens of contributors, <!-- more --> thousands of installs, three appearances at BlackHat Arsenal and a little over 50,000 LOCs written. And that just skims the surface. I am so proud to be a part of something like this.</p>

<p>Up to this point each of us has been contributing in our spare time. Internally we were paying it forward to so many people that helped us. However, recently we&rsquo;ve hit a tough point. To be able to support the community with something worth using, we need to take a chance in offering a paid option for enterprise customers.</p>

<p>All of the information is on the Services and Support page (<a href="https://www.serpicoproject.com/support">https://www.serpicoproject.com/support</a>) or send an e-mail to enterprise &ndash;at&mdash; serpicoproject.com.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
